我们追它做什么
Why are we chasing it?
因为它是淡紫色的危险
It's mauve and dangerous
而且再过30秒就要撞到伦敦市中心了
and about 30 seconds from London.
打扰一下 我正在找这么一个东西
Excuse me, there's this thing I need to find,
应该是几天前从天上掉下来的…
would've fallen from the sky...
南希 我在找的那个东西
Nancy, the thing I'm looking for,
你知道我在说什么 对吗
you know what I'm talking about, don't you?
我接住你了 你没事了
I've got you, you're fine.
你好
Hello.
在下杰克·哈克尼斯
Jack Harkness,
我这一路上听说了你不少事迹
I've heard all about you on the way over.
现在是1941年 伦敦闪击战还在进行
It's 1941, the height of the London Blitz
伦敦的上空还出现了别的东西
and something else has fallen on London.
他说有艘战舰
He said it was a warship,
他偷走了 藏起来了
he stole it, parked it somewhere out there,
没多久就会被炸弹炸到
somewhere a bomb's going to fall on it
除非我们开个价买下来
unless we make him an offer.
这是个骗局
It's a con.
我骗了你们 这就是我的真面目
I was conning you, that's what I am,
我是一个骗子
I'm a con man.
妈咪
Mummy.
有东西追着你和其他孩子
There's something chasing you and the other kids.
妈咪 妈咪
Mummy, mummy.
别让他碰到你
You mustn't let him touch ya.
被他碰到了会怎么样
What happens if he touches me?
你会变得和他一样
It makes you like him.
大家快出去 躲到后花园另一头的篱笆下面
Right, everybody out, across the back garden and under the fence.
快点 动起来
Now, go, move!
到处都是这些家伙
You'll find them everywhere,
每张病床上 每个病房里 成百上千
in every bed in every ward, hundreds of them.
他们的伤势完全相同
They've all got the same injuries,
手背上的伤疤
scarring on the back of the hand
防毒面具似乎和皮肤焊接在一起了
and the gas mask seems to be fused to the flesh.
死因是什么
What was the cause of death?
他们没死
They're not dead!
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
是我 南希
It's me Nancy!
别被他们碰到
Don't let 'em touch you.
被他们碰到了会怎样
What happens if they touch us?
你会成为他们的一员
You're looking at it!
妈咪
Mummy!
回你的房间去
Go to your room!
我说真的 我对你很生气
I mean it. I'm very, very angry with you.
我非常非常不高兴
I'm very, very cross.
回 你 的 房 间 去
Go...to...your...room!
真高兴这招起作用了
I'm really glad that worked.
不然这作为遗言也太糟糕了
Those would have been terrible last words.
神秘博士第一季第十集
博士之舞
编剧 史蒂文·莫法特
杰米
Jamie...
他们为什么都戴着防毒面具
Why are they all wearing gas masks?
不是戴着
They're not.
这些面具和他们血肉相连
Those masks are flesh and bone.
你的骗局是怎么操作的
How was your con supposed to work?
其实很简单
Simple enough, really.
找一些无害的太空垃圾
Find some harmless piece of space junk,
让最近的时间特工追踪回地球
let the nearest Time Agent track it back to Earth,
让他以为这东西很昂贵 给他开个价
convince him it's valuable, and name a price.
当他付了一半的定金以后
When he's put 50% up-front, oops,
突然一枚德国导弹从天而降毁了一切
a German bomb falls on it, destroys it forever.
他永远都不知道自己到底买了什么
He never gets to see what he's paid for,
永远不知道自己被骗了
never knows he's been had.
我再用他给的钱请他喝一杯
I buy him a drink with his own money and
讨论讨论时运不济的问题
we discuss dumb luck.
这个骗局天衣无缝
The perfect, self-cleaning con.
是啊 完美
Yeah. Perfect.
利用伦敦大轰炸来洗脱自己再合适不过了
The London Blitz is great for self-cleaners.
要是想度假的话庞贝挺合适的
Pompeii's nice if you want to make a vacation of it, though.
不过你可得给火山爆发的那天设个闹钟
But you've got to set your alarm for Volcano Day.
感觉你有点不高兴
Getting a hint of disapproval.
看看这个房间
Take a look around the room.
这就是你所谓的无害垃圾的杰作
This is what your piece of harmless space junk did.
那是个被烧毁的医疗运输机 是空的
It was a burnt-out medical transporter, it was empty.
洛斯
Rose!
我们要走了吗
Are we getting out of here?
我们去楼上
We're going upstairs.
我甚至还编写了飞行程序
I even programmed the flight computer
使它不会降落到生命体上 我没伤害别人
so it wouldn't land on anything living. I harmed no-one!
我不知道发生了什么 但是相信我
I don't know what's happening, but believe me,
这跟我没有关系
I had nothing to do with it.
我来告诉你发生了什么
I'll tell you what's happening.
你忘记给自己设闹钟了
You forgot to set your alarm clock.
今天就是火山爆发的日子
It's Volcano Day!
那是什么
What's that?
警报解除
The all clear.
希望是吧
I wish.
我以为你是杰米
I thought you were Jamie.
爸爸
Dad!
臭丫头
Ruddy kids!
放开我 把手放开
Get off of me! Get your hands off me!
进去进去 把她带进去 总算抓住她了
Oi, you, get in, get in! Get her in there! She's nicked.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock?
博士
Doctor.
你有爆破枪吗
You got a blaster?
有啊
Sure.
你的太空垃圾着陆那晚 有人受伤了
The night your space junk landed, someone was hurt.
伤者就是被带到这里来了
This is where they were taken.
发生了什么
What happened?
我们正要来一探究竟 开门
Let's find out. Get it open.
你的音速起子怎么了
What's wrong with your sonic screwdriver?
没什么
Nothing.
音速爆破枪 51世纪的产物
Sonic blaster, 51st century.
产于维勒佳德的武器工厂
Weapon factories of Villengard.
你去过那些工厂吗
You've been to the factories?
去过一次
Once.
现在没了 主反应器超负荷后就毁了
They're gone now. Destroyed when main reactor went critical
整片地都消失了
vaporised the lot.
如我所说 去过一次
Like I said, once.
现在那是一片香蕉林
There's a banana grove there now.
我喜欢香蕉 香蕉有很多好处
I like bananas. Bananas are good.
爆破图案不错
Nice blast pattern.
数码控制的
Digital.
方形枪
Squareness gun.
是啊
Yeah.
我喜欢
I like it.
你怎么看
What do you think?
有东西逃走了
Something got out of here.
是啊 还有呢
Yeah. And?
某个很强大的东西
Something powerful.
很愤怒
Angry.
很强大 很愤怒
Powerful and angry.
是一个孩子
A child?
我想这就解释了那声"妈咪"
I suppose this explains "Mummy"?
一个孩子怎么可能做出这些事
How could a child do this?
你知道你在哪儿吗
Do you know where you are?
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
你知道自己的处境吗
Are you aware of what's around you?
你看得到吗
Can you. . .See?
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
你想要什么 你是否知道…
What do you want? Do you know what. . . ?
我要我的妈咪
I want my mummy!
你是不是我的妈咪 我要我的妈咪
Are you my mummy? I want my mummy.
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
妈咪 妈咪
Mummy? Mummy?
博士 我听到过这个声音
Doctor, I've heard this voice before.
我也是
Me too.
妈咪
Mummy.
一直在说"你是不是我的妈咪"
Always, " Are you my mummy?"
好像他不知道妈妈是谁
Like he doesn't know.
妈咪
Mummy.
他为什么不知道
Why doesn't he know?
你在吗 妈咪
Are you there, Mummy?
妈咪
Mummy!
警察正在来的路上
The police are on their way.
这桌上的食物花的都是我的钱
I pay for the food on this table.
都是我辛苦挣的血汗钱
The sweat on my brow, that food is.
一滴一滴汗水换来的
The sweat on my brow!
你还想要点别的吗
Anything else you'd like?
我这有一大幢房子呢
I've got a whole house here.
你还想来点什么吗
Anything else you'd like to help yourself to?
好啊
Yeah.
我想要些钢丝钳
I'd like some wire-cutters, please.
就是可以剪断铁丝网的东西
Something that can cut through barbed wire.
再来个手电筒
Oh, and a torch.
别摆出这个表情 劳埃德先生
Don't look like that, Mr. Lloyd. . .
我知道你这有好多工具
I know you got plenty of tools in 'ere,
我已经观察这幢房子好久了
I've been watching this house for ages.
我还想再看看你厨房里的碗柜
And I'd like another look round your kitchen cupboards.
第一次时我有点匆忙
I was in an 'urry the first time.
我想看看有没有我能…
I wanna see if there's something I...
这桌上的食物
The food on this table. . .
这些食物也太多了吧 劳埃德先生
Is an awful lot of food, isn't it, Mr. Lloyd?
比别人家桌子上的多多了
A lot more than on anyone else's table.
大半街坊邻居都认为你太太
Half this street thinks your missus
肯定跟那个屠夫 哈维斯托克先生有一腿
must be messing about with Mr. Haverstock, the butcher.
但其实她没有 对吧
But she's not, is she?
其实是你
You are.
钢丝钳 手电筒 食物
Wire-cutters. Torch. Food.
在我离开前还想借用一下你的厕所
And I'd like to use your bathroom before I leave, please.
瞧啊
Oh, look!
你流下辛勤的汗水了
There's the sweat on your brow!
妈咪 求你了 妈咪
Mummy? Please, Mummy? Mummy?
博士
Doctor?
你能感觉到吗
Can you sense it?
感觉到什么
Sense what?
从墙里透出来
Coming out of the walls.
你能感觉到吗
Can you feel it?
妈咪
Mummy?
人脑真是小得可怜
Funny little human brains!
你们到底怎么活下来的
How do you get around in those things?
他一紧张就会羞辱别的物种
When he's stressed, he likes to insult species.
洛斯 我在思考
Rose, I'm thinking!
刮脸刮伤了自己
Cuts himself shaving,
都要花半天时间去挖苦没他聪明的物种
he does half an hour on life-forms he's cleverer than.
轰炸区有一些艰难存活的孩子
There are these children. Living rough, round the bomb sites.
空袭间隙他们会出来寻找食物
They come out during air raids looking for food.
妈咪 求你了
Mummy, please?
试想 当这个不明物体着陆时
Suppose they were there when this thing,
他们刚好在那儿
whatever it was, landed.
那是艘无害的医疗运输机
It was a med-ship, it was harmless!
你一直在强调无害
You keep saying harmless.
试想其中一人被感染了 转化了
Suppose one of them was affected, altered.
怎么转化
Altered how?
我在这儿呢
I'm here!
它很害怕
It's afraid,
非常害怕 还很强大
terribly afraid. And powerful. . .
它现在还不知道 但是会知道的
it doesn't know it yet. But it will do.
它的力量堪比神明
It's got the power of a God and
我刚刚却命令他回房间了
I just sent it to its room!
博士
Doctor. . .
我在这儿呢
I'm here!
你看不到我吗
Can't you see me?
那是什么声音
What's that noise?
磁带结束了
End of the tape.
磁带三十秒前就到头了
End of the tape. It ran out about 30 seconds ago.
我在这儿呢 你们看不到我吗
I'm here now, can't you see me?
我把它送回了自己的房间
I sent it to its room.
这里就是它的房间
This is its room!
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
妈咪
Mummy?
博士
Doctor?
听我指令 往门那边跑
OK, on my signal, make for the door...
妈咪
Mummy?
就现在
Now!
妈咪
Mummy?
快走 别把香蕉弄丢了
Go, now, don't drop the banana!
为什么
Why not?
香蕉富含钾元素
Good source of potassium!
给我
Gimme that!
妈咪 你是不是我的妈咪
Mummy? Are you my mummy?
数码重构
Digital rewind.
好一招偷天换日
Nice switch.
这是维勒佳德林子产的
It's from the groves of Villengard
就知道会派上用场
thought it was appropriate.
维勒佳德中心真的有一片香蕉林吗
There's really a banana grove in the heart in Villengard?
是你把工厂炸了的吗
And you did that?
香蕉有很多好处
Bananas are good.
博士
Doctor!
快走
Come on!
妈咪
Mummy!
它们准备在它出来前把我们困在这儿
It's keeping us here till it can get at us!
它在控制它们吗
It's controlling them?
它就是它们
It is them.
它是这家医院里的每一个活物
It's every living thing in this hospital.
这东西有音速爆破
OK. This can function as a sonic blaster,
音速加农炮
a sonic cannon
还有三相声波干扰器
and it's a triple-enfolded sonic disruptor.
博士你有什么
Doc, what you got?
我有个音速…算了
I've got a sonic, uh,. . . Never mind.
什么
What?
它是音速的 就说到这儿吧
It's sonic, OK, let's leave it at that.
干扰器还是加农炮 是什么
Disruptor, cannon, what?
就是音速的 纯音速的 我音速武装了
It's sonic, totally sonic, I am sonic-ed up!
音速什么
A sonic what?
起子
AScrewdriver!
下去
Going down!
博士 你没事吧
Doctor, are you OK?
你应该事先提醒一下
Could've used a warning.
好歹说个谢谢吧
Oh, the gratitude!
谁没事带个音速起子
Who has a sonic screwdriver?
我喽
I do!
灯呢
Lights?
谁会看着一个音速起子想
Who looks at a screwdriver and thinks,
"这玩意可以再音速点"
"Ooh-hoo this could be a little more sonic?"
怎么了 你就不会闲得没事干吗
What? You never been bored?
肯定有个电灯开关
There's gotta be a light switch.
从没有过漫漫长夜 从没思绪万千过吗
Never had a long night? Never had a lot of cabinets to put up?
妈咪
Mummy!
门
Door!
妈咪 妈咪 妈咪
Mummy? Mummy? Mummy?
该死
Damn it!
妈咪
Mummy?
这些特殊功能真的耗电很快
It's the special features, they really drain the battery.
还用电池
The battery?!
太逊了
It's so lame!
我本来准备换一个的
I was going to send for another one.
但是有人非得把那个工厂炸了
But somebody's gotta blow up the factory.
我知道 第一次见面他就把我的工作炸没了
I know. First day I met him, he blew my job up.
这基本上就是他的交流方式
That's pratically how he communicates.
这扇门应该可以撑个一会儿
OK, that door should hold it for a bit.
这扇门 连墙都挡不住它啊
The door? The wall didn't stop it!
它总得先找到我们啊 我们还没完呢
It's got to find us first! Come on, we're not done yet!
情况评估
Assets, assets!
我配备有一根香蕉
Well, I've got a banana
然后你还可以用起子装几个书架
and in a pinch you could put up some shelves.
窗子呢
Window?
封上了 外面可是七层楼
Barred. Sheer drop outside, seven storeys.
没有别的出口了
And no other exits.
看来一下子就评估完了 是不是
Well, the assets conversation went in a flash, didn't it?
你在哪找到这家伙的
So where'd you pick this one up, then?
博士
Doctor!
她挂在一个拦截气球上
She was hanging from a barrage balloon,
我有一艘隐形飞船 不救她都不行
I had an invisible space ship. . . I never stood a chance.
首先 我们必须离开这儿
OK! One. . . We've gotta get out of here.
第二 我们没法离开这儿 有什么遗漏吗
Two. . .we can't get out of here. Have I missed anything?
有
Yeah.
杰克刚刚消失了
Jack just disappeared.
就知道 你们都在这儿干什么
Thought as much. What are all of you doing 'ere?
我说过了每晚都得去不同的房子里
Different house every night, I told ya!
我们以为你死了 或着跑了
We thought you were dead or you'd run off.
我没这么想 我知道你会回来找我们的
I didn't. I knew you'd come back for us.
在那堆垃圾里找到这个老古董
Found that old thing in the junk.
他觉得自己能写字了
Thinks he's can write now.
写封信给我爸爸
Writing a letter to me dad.
你连你爸爸在哪儿都不知道
You don't even know where your dad is.
你打算怎么寄
And how you gonna send it?
不知道 塞信封里
I dunno, stick it in an envelope.
你不会读书也不会写字
You can't even read or write.
我不需要啊 我有这台机器
I don't need to, I've got a machine!
你能别发出那种声音了吗
Will you stop making that noise?
对不起 吉姆
I'm sorry, Jim.
继续吧 想给你爸爸写信就写吧
On you go, you write a letter to your dad if you want to.
我知道我们应该去别的地方
I know we should've went somewhere else,
但我们需要你 给我们出主意
but we need you, see, for the thinking.
要是我没回来呢
What if I wasn't 'ere?
要是有天晚上我没能回来找你们呢
What if one night I didn't come back for ya?
现在正在打仗 人们活着出去
There's a war on, people go out.
未必能活着回来 到时候你们怎么办
They don't always come back. It happens. What would you do then?
这些是钢丝钳
They're wire cutters.
我要你好好想想
I need you to think about that.
总得有人来照顾他们
Someone's gotta look after this lot.
为什么 你要去哪儿
Why? You going somewhere?
轰炸区
The bomb site.
火车站那边
The one at the railway station.
为什么
Why?
那个孩子
The Child.
他就是在那里遇害的
That's where he was killed.
那里就是一切的开端 我要去查清楚
That's where it all started. And I'm gonna find out how.
他会抓住你的 然后他们就会来抓我们
He'll get you. And then he'll come for us.
他总是跟着我们
He always comes for us!
不
No.
厄尼 不是你们
Ernie, he doesn't.
他一直想找的是我
He always comes after me.
我有些事没告诉过你
There are things I haven't told ya.
有些事我不能告诉你
Things I can't tell ya.
只要你们和我一起
As long as you're with me,
你们就很危险
you're in danger.
即使是现在 你们也因为我而身处险境
Even right now, you're in danger because of me.
是你保护着我们的安全
You're the one that keeps us safe.
你这么觉得吗 厄尼
You think so, Ernie?
那回答我
Then answer this.
既然吉姆就坐在你旁边
Jim is sitting there right next to ya. . .
那是谁在打字
So who's typing?
他来了吗
Is he coming?
厄尼 只要你们跟我一起
Ernie, as long as you're with me. . .
他总会来的
he's always coming.
有很多蔬菜 细嚼慢咽
Plenty of greens. And chew your food!
妈咪 妈咪 你是不是我的妈咪
他凭空消失了
OK, so he vanished into thin air.
为什么总是长得帅的人这么做
Why is it always the great-looking ones who do that?
我尽量认为我没被冒犯到
I'm making an effort not to be insulted.
我是说…人类
I mean. . . Men.
好 谢谢 这样好多了
OK, thanks, that really helped.
洛斯 博士 听得到吗
Rose? Doctor? Can you hear me?
我回到飞船上了 用了紧急传送
Back on my ship...Used the emergency teleport.
不好意思不能带你们一起
Sorry I couldn't take you,
安全密匙只能识别我的分子结构
it's security-keyed to my molecular structure.
我正在努力 坚持住
I'm working on it. Hanging there.
你怎么和我们说话的
How are you speaking to us?
即时通信 我能通过扬声器对任何人说话
Om-Com - I can call anything with a speaker grill.
这真是个巧合
Now there's a coincidence!
什么
What is?
那孩子也会即时通信
The Child can Om-Com too.
是吗
It can?
只要有扬声器
Anything with a speaker grill.
甚至是塔迪斯的电话
Even the TARDIS phone.
你是说那孩子能跟我们通话
What, you mean the Child can phone us?
我能听到哦 来找你们了 我来了
And I can hear you. Coming to find you. Coming to find you!
博士 你听得到吗
Doctor, can you hear that?
一清二楚
Loud and clear.
我试试隔离信号 我只能帮到这里了
I'll try to block out the signal. Least I can do.
我来找你了 妈咪
Coming to find you, Mummy.
记得这个吗 洛斯
Remember this one, Rose?
我们的歌
Our song.
你在干什么
What you doing?
想找到水泥的共振模式 弄松围栏
Trying to set up a resonation pattern in the concrete, loosen the bars.
你觉得他不会回来了对吧
You don't think he's coming back, do ya?
我可说不准
Wouldn't bet my life.
你为什么不信任他
Why don't you trust him?
你为什么信任他
Why do you?
他救过我
Saved my life.
耍小聪明 炫耀自己的小花招
Bloke-wise, that's up there with flossing.
我信任他是因为他像你
I trust him cos he's like you.
只不过更会约会和跳舞而已
Except with dating and dancing.
什么
What?
你就这么假定…
You just assume I'm...
什么
What?
你就直接假定我不会…跳舞
You just assume I don't... dance.
什么 你是想告诉我你会跳舞吗
What? Are you telling me you do dance?
我都九百岁了 也经历过不少了
900 years old, me. I've been around a bit.
我觉得你应该可以假设我是会跳舞的
I think you can assume at some point I've danced.
你
You?
有问题吗
你跳舞的话不会导致宇宙自爆之类的吗
Doesn't the universe implode or something if you dance?
我还是有两下子的 不想到处吹嘘而已
Well, I've got the moves but I wouldn't wanna boast.
你有两下子
You've got the moves?
来让我见识见识
Show me your moves!
洛斯 我…我正在找共振频率呢
Rose, I'm, I'm trying to resonate concrete.
杰克会回来的 他会救我们出去的
Jack'll be back. He'll get us out.
来吧 跳个舞又不会导致世界末日
So come on. The world doesn't end cos the Doctor dances.
防空气球
Barrage balloon?
什么
What?
你当时挂在一个防空气球上
You were hanging from a barrage balloon.
是的
Oh, yeah.
那是你离开后两分钟的事
About two minutes after you left me.
在伦敦上空几百米的地方
Thousands of feet above London.
德国正在进行空袭 胸前就是英国国旗
Middle of a German air raid, Union Jack all over my chest!
我和好多人一起旅行过
I've travelled with a lot of people,
但你吸引危险的能力简直是绝无仅有
but you're setting new records for jeopardy friendly.
这就是你跳的舞吗 我可以教教你
Is this you dancing? Cos I've got notes.
挂在绳子上
Hanging from a rope.
身处伦敦上空几百米 没有瘀伤刮痕
Thousands of feet above London. Not a cut, not a bruise.
我知道 杰克上校帮我治好了
Yeah, I know. Captain Jack fixed me up.
现在改叫他杰克上校吗
We're calling him Captain Jack now?
他叫杰克 而且是个上校
Well, his name's Jack, and he's a captain.
他不算上校 洛斯
He's not really a captain, Rose!
你知道我怎么想吗
You know what I think?
我觉得你这是上校之间的嫉妒
I think you're experiencing captain envy.
你会发现你的脚已经跃跃欲试了
You will find your feet at the end of your legs.
也许你不介意动一动
You may care to move 'em.
就算他曾是上校 也已经被免职了
If ever he was a captain he's been defrocked.
是吗 真可惜我错过了那个时刻
Yeah? Shame I missed that.
其实是我辞职了
Actually I quit.
没人能免我的职
Nobody takes my frock.
大多数人被传送的时候都是有感觉的
Most people notice when they've been teleported.
你俩太陶醉了 不好意思拖了这么久
You guys are so sweet. Sorry about the delay.
我得把导航系统关掉 才能覆盖传送安全协议
Had to take the nav-com off-line to override the teleport security.
你覆盖你自己的协议 也要花上十分钟吗
You can spend ten minutes overriding your own protocols?
也许你应该记得这艘船主人到底是谁
Maybe you should remember whose ship it is!
我记得 她可美了
Oh, I do. She was gorgeous.
正如我跟她所说的
Like I told her. . .
五分钟后回来
be back in five minutes.
这是一艘丘拉船
This is a Chula ship.
是的 和那艘医疗船一样
Yeah, just like that medical transporter.
不过这艘船可是很危险的
Only this one is dangerous.
这就是治好我手的东西
They're what fixed up my hands up.
杰克叫它们
Jack called them...
纳米机器人 纳米基因体
Nanobots? Nanogenes?
纳米基因体
Nanogenes, yeah.
亚原子机器人
Subatomic robots.
这儿有上百万个
There's millions of them in here.
看到没 我们降落到控制台时我手烧伤了
See? Burned my hand on the console when we landed.
现在好多了 舱门一封闭它们就开始工作
All better now. They activate when the bulkhead's sealed,
查看你的伤势 治疗你受到的伤害
check you out for damage, fix any physical flaws.
带我们到坠毁点
Take us to the crash site.
我要看看你的太空垃圾
I need to see your space junk.
我把导航系统重启就好
Soon as I get the nav-com back on line.
请自便吧
Make yourselves comfortable.
继续你们俩之前…做的事吧
Carry on with whatever it was you were...doing.
我们在谈论跳舞
We were talking about dancing.
看上去可不像谈论
It didn't look like talking.
感觉也不像在跳舞
Didn't feel like dancing.
站住 不许动
Halt! Don't move!
所以你曾是个时间特工 但现在你想骗他们
So you used to be a Time Agent, and now you're trying to con 'em?
如果这样说能让我不那么下作的话
If it makes me sound any better,
我不是为了钱
it's not for the money.
那为什么
For what?
当我还是他们中的一员时 有天早上醒来
Woke up one morning when I was still working for them,
发现他们偷走了我两年的记忆 我想要回来
found they'd stolen two years of my memories. I'd like them back.
他们偷走了你的记忆
They stole your memories?
我的两年
Two years of my life.
完全不知道我干了什么
No idea what I did.
你那位朋友不信任我
Your friend over there doesn't trust me
据我所知 他这样做是明智的
and for all I know, he's right not to.
好 我们能走了
Ok! We're good to go!
去坠毁地点吗
The crash site?
你在这儿啊 好点了吗
As you were. You feeling any better?
好点了 长官
Just a touch, sir.
把她锁在詹金斯视线之内
Chain her up where Jenkins can keep an eye on her.
不 别把我和他关在一起
No! Not in here! Not with him.
你不想被关在这儿 当初就不该闯进来
You shouldn't have broken in here if you didn't want to stay.
你不懂 别把我和他关一起
You don't understand! Not with him!
这里是军事禁地 小姐
This is a restricted area, Miss.
你可以先在这儿坐一会
You can sit here for a bit,
我们准备问你几个问题
we're going to have to ask you a few questions.
找到了这些 长官
Found these, sir.
很专业嘛 有点太专业了
Very professional. A little bit too professional.
你不是一不小心路过的吧
Didn't just drop in by accident, then. Didn't you?
我的弟弟死在这里
My little brother died here.
我想查出是什么杀了他
I wanted to find out what killed him.
带点人 去看看篱墙有没有别的破洞
Take the men, check the fence for any other breaches.
搜查这片区域 她可能不是一个人来的
And search the area, she may not have come here alone.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir!
听我说 不能把我留在这里
Please. Listen, you can't leave me here.
看住他 詹金斯
Watch her, Jenkins!
是 妈咪
Yes, Mummy.
詹金斯
Jenkins?
抱歉
Sorry.
长官 我也不知道自己怎么回事
Sir, I don't know what's the matter with me.
把我锁起来没关系 只要别把我关在这里
Look, lock me up, fine, but not here.
求你了 不要在这里
Please, anywhere but here!
你会没事的 小姐
You'll be all right, Miss,
我只是有点…有点…
I'm just a little. . . Just a little. .
你到底怎么回事
What's the matter with you?
求你了 让我走吧
Please. Let me go.
我为什么放你走
Why would I do that?
因为你手背上有道疤
Cos you've got a scar on the back of your hand.
是的 但这跟放你走有什么关系
Oh, yes, but what's that got to do with anything?
而且你感觉自己很难受
And you feel like you're gonna be sick.
感觉好像有东西想拼命钻到你的喉咙里
Like something's forcing its way up your throat.
我知道是因为我见过这种事
I know because I've seen it before.
我怎么了
What's happening to me?
再过一会儿 你就不是你自己了
In a minute you won't be you any more.
你甚至不会记得自己
You won't even remember you.
除非你让我走 不然我也会这样 求你了
And unless you let me go, it's going to happen to me too. Please!
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你妈妈叫什么
What's your mother's name?
玛蒂尔达
Matilda.
你有妻子吗
You got a wife?
有
Yes.
她叫什么
Wife's name?
你有孩子吗
You got kids?
你叫什么
What's your name?
求你了
Please.
让我走吧 你已经太晚了
Let me go. It's too late for you.
对不起 让我走吧
I'm sorry. But please let me go.
你什么意…
What do you m...?
妈…妈咪
M-m-m-mumm-y.
妈…咪…
Mumme-e-e-e!
在那儿呢
Well, there it is!
他们让阿尔吉当差呢 肯定有大事
Hey, they've got Algy on duty. Must be important.
我们必须得过去
We've gotta get past.
我的任务应该就是"引开守卫"吧
Are the words "Distract the guard" Heading in my general direction?
我不觉得这是个好主意
I don't think that'd be such a good idea.
别担心 我能搞定的
Don't worry, I can handle it.
自打我来到这个小镇上
I've got to know Algy quite well,
就认识阿尔吉了 相信我
since I've been in town. Trust me,
你不是他的菜 我来引开他
you're not his type. I'll distract him.
不用等我了
Don't wait up!
放松 他是从51世纪来的
Relax! He's a 51st-century guy.
不过是舞伴挑选标准比较灵活罢了
He's just a bit more flexible when it comes to dancing.
有多灵活
How flexible?
他那个时候你们人类都遍布大半宇宙了
By his time, you lot are spread out across half the galaxy.
什么意思
Meaning?
物种太多 时间太少
So many species, so little time.
这就是我们走出地球以后的任务吗
That's what we do when we get out there? That's our mission?
寻找新生命 然后…
We seek new life and...and...
跳舞
Dance!
小老虎 最近怎么样
Hey, tiger. How's it hanging?
妈咪
Mummy?
阿尔吉 老伙计 是我
Algy, old sport, it's me.
妈咪
Mummy?!
是我啊 杰克
It's me, Jack!
杰克
Jack?
你是不是我的…妈咪
Are you my. . . Mummy?
后退
Stay back!
你们别过来
You men, stay away!
影响开始通过空气传播了 还在加速
The effect's becoming airborne, accelerating.
有什么能保护我们
What's keeping us safe?
没有
Nothing.
他们又来轰炸了
Ah, here they come again.
真会挑时候
All we need!
你不是说这里会投下一颗炸弹吗
Didn't you say a bomb was gonna land here?
别管那个了
Never mind about that.
如果是通过空气传播的 那只剩几小时了
If the contaminant's airborne now, there's hours left.
什么还有几小时
Till what?
毁灭 永远毁灭 所有人类
Till nothing! Forever! For the entire human race.
你们能听到有人唱歌吗
And can anyone else hear singing?
*摇篮摇啊折树梢*
*When the wind blows the cradle will rock*
*折树梢啊摇篮落*
*When the bow breaks the cradle will fall*
*摇篮落啊掉宝宝*
*Down will come baby cradle and all...*
*风儿吹啊摇篮摇*
*Rock-a-bye baby...On the tree tops*
*摇篮摇啊折树梢*
*When the wind blows the cradle will rock*
看到没 医疗船
You see? Just an ambulance!
那是用来医疗的
That's an ambulance?
有点难解释 这…
It's hard to explain, it's...
是另一个世界的
it's from another world.
他们一直想进去
They've been trying to get in.
那当然了
Of course they have.
他们觉得自己发现了希特勒的秘密武器
They think they've got their hands on Hitler's secret weapon.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
等你看到这里面是空的 你就知道这事跟我没关系
When you see this thing is empty you'll know I had nothing to do with it.
上次可没这样
Didn't happen last time.
上次可没坠毁
It hadn't crashed last time.
肯定有紧急协议
There'll be emergency protocols.
博士 那是什么
Doctor, what is that?
妈咪
Mummy.
博士
Doctor!
上校 守好大门
Captain, secure those gates.
为什么
Why?
照做就是
Just do it!
南希 你怎么进来的
Nancy, how did you get in here?
剪掉铁丝网
Cut the wire.
带洛斯过去 设置2428-D
Show Rose. Setting 2428-D.
什么
What?
修补铁丝网 快去
Re-attaches barbed wire. Go!
你是谁 你们都是什么人
Who are you? Who are any of you?
跟你说了你也不会信
Never believe me if I told ya.
我都见识过另一个世界的医疗船了
You just told me that was an ambulance from another world.
到处都是戴着防毒面具找妈妈的人
People are running round with gas mask heads calling for their mummies,
天上又随时都可能掉下德国人的炸弹
the sky's full of Germans took bombs or something.
说吧 你觉得我现在还有什么不能相信的吗
Tell me, do you think there's anything left I couldn't believe?
我们是来自未来的时空旅行者
We're time travellers from the future.
你疯了
Mad, you are!
我们真的有台时空机器
We have a time travel machine. Seriously.
不是那个
It's not that.
好吧 你们有时空穿越机器 我相信你
All right, you got a time travel machine, I'll believe ya.
我什么都信
Believe anything, me.
但是哪有什么未来
But what future?
南希 这不是末日
Nancy, this isn't the end.
我知道现在看起来很糟
I know how it looks,
但这不是世界末日
it's not the end of the world or anything.
怎么可能
How can you say that?
看看这周围
Look at it.
听我说
Listen to me.
我出生在这个城市
I was born in this city.
我就是本地人 生活在五十年后
I'm from here. In like 50 years time.
来自这里
From here?
我是个伦敦人
I'm a Londoner.
来自你们的未来
From your future.
但…但你不是
But...But you're not...
什么
What?
德国人
German.
南希 德国人打不过来的 他们输了
Nancy, the Germans don't come here. They don't win.
别告诉别人我这么和你说的
Don't tell anyone I told you so.
但你知道吗 你们赢了
But you know what? You win.
我们赢了
We win?
来吧
Come on!
空的 你自己看
It's empty. Look at it.
你觉得丘拉医疗船里能装什么
What do you expect in a Chula Medical Transporter?
绷带和咳嗽药水吗
Bandages? Cough drops?
洛斯
Rose?
我不知道
I dunno.
你知道的
Yes, you do.
纳米基因体
Nanogenes!
这不是空的 上校
It wasn't empty, Captain.
这里的纳米基因体足够重建一个物种了
There was enough nanogenes in there to rebuild a species.
噢 天哪
Oh, God.
现在明白了吧
Getting it now, are we?
飞船坠毁时 纳米基因体都逃走了
When the ship crashes, the nanogenes escape.
成万上亿个
Billions upon billions of them.
准备修复全世界所有瘀伤割伤
Ready to fix all the cuts and bruises in the whole world.
但它们首先发现的 是一个死去的孩子
But what they find first is a dead child.
也许是那晚早些时候被杀的
Probably killed earlier that night.
还戴着防毒面具
And wearing a gas mask.
他们让他重生了吗 真的做得到吗
And they brought him back to life? They can do that?
生命是什么 很简单
What's life? Life's easy.
物质的巧妙组合而已
A quirk of matter.
是大自然使肉保持鲜活的方式
Nature's way of keeping meat fresh.
对纳米基因体而言不是问题
Nothing to a nanogene.
但有个麻烦
One problem though.
这些纳米基因体和你飞船上的不一样
These nanogenes, they're not like the ones on your ship.
这些从来没见过人类
This lot have never seen a human being before.
不知道人类应该是怎么样的
Don't know what a human being's supposed to look like.
它们只有那具小男孩的尸体
All they've got to go on is one little body,
而且也只有一些残骸
and there's not a lot left.
但它们还是继续
But they carry right on,
按照设定好的程序去做
they do what they're programmed to do,
它们修补好尸体
they patch it up.
分不清面罩和骨头 但他们尽力了
Can't tell what's gas mask and what's skull but they do their best.
然后它们飞走了 还有活要干呢
Then off they fly, off they go, work to be done!
现在 它们以为自己知道了人类的样子
Cos you see, now they think they know what people should look like.
是时候修复好其他所有人了 它们不会停手
And it's time to fix all the rest. And they won't ever stop.
它们永远永远不会停手
They won't ever, ever stop.
所有人类都将被摧毁
The entire human race is gonna be torn down
并以一个恐惧的孩子为原型重铸
and rebuilt in the form of one terrified child,
到处找妈妈
looking for its mother.
谁也阻止不了它们
And nothing in the world can stop it!
我不知情
I didn't know.
妈咪 妈咪
Mummy, Mummy.
洛斯
Rose!
戴面罩的人都被吸引过来了
It's bringing the gas-mask people here.
这艘船以为遭到了攻击 正在召集部下
The ship thinks it's under attack. It's calling all the troops.
这是标准协议
Standard protocol.
但面罩人不是士兵啊
But the gas-mask people aren't troops!
现在是了 这是一艘军用医疗船
They are now. This is a battlefield ambulance.
纳米基因体不仅会治好你
The nanogenes don't just fix you up,
还会让你做好上战场的准备
they get you ready for the front line.
全副武装 重新编制
Equip you, programme you. . .
所以那孩子才会这么强壮
That's why the Child's so strong?
才会进行隔空通讯
Why it could do that phoning thing?
现在他是全副武装的丘拉战士
It's a fully-equipped Chula Warrior, yes.
所有武器都握在一个歇斯底里的四岁儿童手中
All that weapons tech in the hands of an hysterical four-year-old,
想找他的妈妈
looking for his Mummy
现在有了一大群这样的人
and now there's an army of them.
妈咪
Mummy!
他们为什么不攻击
Why don't they attack?
合格的好士兵
Good little soldiers.
会等待指挥官下达命令
Waiting for their commander.
那个孩子
The Child!
杰米
Jamie.
什么
What?
不叫"那个孩子" 他叫杰米
Not the Child, Jamie.
炸弹轰炸之前还有多久
So how long until the bomb falls?
随时都有可能
Any second.
怎么了 上校
What's the matter, Captain?
太靠近火山口了吗
Bit close to the volcano for you?
他只是一个小男孩
He's just a little boy.
我知道
I know.
他只是一个想找妈妈的小男孩
He's just a little boy who wants his Mummy.
我知道
I know.
世上哪个小男孩不是
There isn't a little boy born who
为救自己的妈咪不惜毁灭世界
wouldn't tear the world apart to save his Mummy.
而这个小男孩真的做得到
And this little boy can.
那我们怎么办
So what are we gonna do?
我不知道
I don't know.
都是我的错
It's my fault.
不是
No.
是的 都是我的错
It is. It's all my fault.
你怎么可能是你的…
How can it be your...?
妈咪
Mummy!
南希 你几岁了
Nancy, what age are you?
二十 二十一 比你看上去更年长吧
20, 21? Older than you look, yes?
博士 那个炸弹 我们没时间了
Doctor, that bomb... We've got seconds!
你可以把我们都传送走
You can teleport us out.
你们不行 现在启用了导航系统
Not you guys. The nav-com's back on line,
覆盖协议要花上很久
gonna take too long to override the protocols.
今天就是火山爆发之日
So it's Volcano Day.
做你该做的事吧
Do what you've got to do!
杰克
Jack?
你五年前几岁 十五六岁吗
How old were you five years ago, 15? 16?
反正已经可以生小孩了吧
Old enough to give birth anyway.
他不是你的弟弟 对吧
He's not your brother, is he?
1941年 十几岁的单身母亲
Teenage single mother in 1941.
你藏了起来 你撒了谎
So you hid. You lied.
你甚至骗了他
You even lied to him.
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
他会一直问 南希 不会停下来
He's gonna keep asking, Nancy. He's never gonna stop.
告诉他吧
Tell him.
南希 人类的未来都在你手里
Nancy, the future of the human race is in your hands.
相信我 告诉他
Trust me and tell him.
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
是的 是的 我是你的妈咪
Yes. Yes, I am your mummy.
妈咪
Mummy?
我在这儿呢
I'm here!
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
我在这儿呢
I'm here.
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
是的
Yes.
你是不是我的妈咪
Are you my mummy?
他不懂 他的躯体已经所剩无几了
He doesn't understand, there's not enough of him left.
我是你的妈咪
I am your mummy.
我永远都是你的妈咪
I will always be your mummy.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我真的 真的对不起
I am so, so sorry.
怎么了
What's happening?
博士 她在转变 我们…
Doctor, it's changing her, we've...
加油吧 拜托
Come on, please!
来啊 你们这儿些聪明的基因体 快搞清楚啊
Come on, you clever little nanogenes. Figure it out!
妈咪 她就是那个妈咪
The mother, she's the mother.
信息肯定足够了
It's gotta be enough information.
弄明白啊
Figure it out!
怎么回事
What's happening?!
看到了吗
See?
它们识别出他俩有相同的DNA
Recognising the same DNA!
拜托
Oh, come on!
让我过上安心的一天吧
Gimme a day like this!
让我瞧瞧吧
Gimme this one!
欢迎回来 你会大爱二十年后的流行乐的
Welcome back! 20 years to pop music, you're gonna love it.
怎么回事
What happened?
纳米基因体识别出了上层信息
The nanogenes recognised the superior information.
父母的DNA
The parent DNA.
它们没改变你 因为你改变了它们
They didn't change you, because you changed them.
知子莫若母啊
Mother knows best.
杰米
Jamie...
博士 炸弹…
Doctor, that bomb. . .
已经处理好了
Taken care of it.
怎么处理的
How?
心理学
Psychology.
博士
Doctor!
好小子
Good lad.
炸弹已经进入引爆阶段了
The bomb's already commenced detonation.
我已经将其静止了 但持续不了太久
I've put it in stasis, but it won't last long!
计划有变 我们不需要炸弹了
Change of plan! Don't need the bomb.
你能处理掉吗 越安全越好
Can you get rid of it, safely as you can?
洛斯
Rose?
再见
Goodbye!
顺便 我很喜欢你的T恤
By the way...Loved the T-shirt!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
软件补丁
Software patch.
得把升级补丁发出去
Gonna e-mail the upgrade.
你想看我跳舞 洛斯 我就让你看看
You want moves, Rose. I'll give you moves!
每个人都活着 洛斯
Everybody lives, Rose.
终于有了一次
Just this once!
大家都活了下来
Everybody lives!
康斯坦丁医生 永远不会丢下他的病人
Dr. Constantine, who never left his patients.
活过来了 康斯坦医生
Back on your feet, Constant Doctor.
现在世界还没做好失去你的打算
World doesn't want to get by without you just yet
对此我没有异议
and I don't blame it one bit.
这些都是你的病人 现在都好多了
These are your patients. All better now.
是的 看上去是的
Yes. Yes, so it seems.
他们好像都在一个废弃的火车站里
They also seem to be standing around in a disused railway station.
有什么特别的理由吗
Is there any particular reason for that?
你也知道 经费不足嘛
Yeah, well, you know, cutbacks.
听着 不管他们之前有什么问题
Listen, whatever was wrong with them in the past
你可能会发现他们都已经被治愈了
you're probably gonna find that they're cured.
只要让他们知道你是个多棒的医生就行了
Just tell 'em what a great doctor you are,
别太大惊小怪 行吗
don't make a big thing of it. OK?
康斯坦丁医生
Dr. Constantine.
哈克特太太 您看上去好多了
Mrs. Harcourt, how much better you're looking!
我的腿都长回来了
My leg's grown back!
我去医院时 我只有一条腿
When I come to the hospital, I had one leg!
现在兵荒马乱的
Well, there is a war on,
你会不会是数错了
is it possible you miscounted?
你们几个 还有很多事要做呢
Right, you lot, lots to do.
打败德国人 拯救世界
Beat the Germans, save the world,
别忘了建立福利社会
don't forget the welfare state!
设定为大家都撤离后启动自毁程序
Setting this to self destruct soon as everybody's clear.
历史上说这里曾经有一场大爆炸
History says there was an explosion here.
我怎么会反对历史呢
Who am I to argue with history?
你一般排第一个
Usually the first in line.
纳米基因体会收拾这些烂摊子 进入关闭状态
The nanogenes will clean up their mess and switch themselves off
因为我已经给它们下达了指令
cos I just told them to.
南希和杰米会去找康斯坦丁医生寻求帮助
Nancy and Jamie will go to Dr. Constantine for help...ditto.
总而言之 一切都处理好了 太棒了
All in all, all things considered, fantastic!
看看你 开心得和圣诞老人似的
Look at you, beaming like you're Father Christmas!
谁说我不是 你12岁的红自行车是谁给的
Who says I'm not? Red bicycle when you were 12.
什么
What?
所有人都活着 洛斯
Ands everybody lives, Rose.
大家都活着 我需要多点今天这样的日子
Everybody lives. I need more days like this!
博士
Doctor...
来吧 问我问题吧 我正在燃烧呢
Go on, ask me anything. I'm on fire.
杰克怎么了
What about Jack?
他为什么要说再见
Why did he say goodbye?
电脑
OK, computer. . .
这颗炸弹能保持静态多久
how long can we keep the bomb in stasis?
静态状态已达90%
Stasis decaying at 90% cycle.
三分钟后爆炸
Detonation in three minutes.
我们能把它扔出去吗
Can we jettison it?
任何尝试丢出此装置的动作都会引爆炸弹
Any attempt to jettison the device will precipitate detonation.
概率100%
100% probability.
我们可以把它放到逃生舱里
We could stick it in an escape pod?
这艘船没有逃生舱
There is no escape pod on board.
我口误了 我可以进到逃生舱里
OK, see the flaw in that. I'll get in the escape pod.
飞船没有逃生舱
There is no escape pod on board.
你全都查看过了吗
Did you check everywhere?
确认
Affirmative.
船舱内部呢
Under the sink?
确认
Affirmative.
好吧
Ok.
百分制来算 我死的可能性到底有多大
Out of 100, exactly how dead am I?
杰克上校将在两分钟内死亡 可能性为100%
Termination of Captain Jack harkness in under two minutes, 100% probability.
好极了 谢谢
Lovely, thanks.
谢谢你提供数据
Good to know the numbers.
不客气
You're welcome.
那好吧
OK, then!
我们还是启用紧急协议417吧
Think we'd better initiate emergency protocol 417.
确认
Affirmative.
苦艾加太多了
Ooh, a little too much vermouth.
看我以后还来不来
See if I come here again.
有趣的是
Funny thing...
上一次我被宣判死刑时
Last time I was sentenced to death,
我早餐要了四杯超浓缩伏特加
I ordered four hyper-vodkas for my breakfast.
后来发生的一切都模模糊糊了
All a bit of a blur after that.
只记得跟两个行刑手一起在床上醒来
Woke up in bed with both my executioners.
那一对真可爱
Mmm, lovely couple.
他们俩一直保持联系
They stayed in touch.
不能说大多数行刑手都是那样的吧
Can't say that about most executioners.
不管怎么说
Anyway...
谢谢你为我做的一切 电脑
Thanks for everything, computer. . .
我很开心
it's been great.
快点啊
Well, hurry up, then!
好 然后转圈
OK...and turn.
好 再试试让我转圈
OK, try and spin me again.
但这次别把我的手别在背后了
But this time don't get my arm up my back!
这又不是摔跤比赛
No extra points for a half-Nelson.
我以前肯定知道怎么跳的 关门行吗
I'm sure I used to know this stuff. Close the door, will you?
你的船都要炸了 残骸会炸得到处都是
Your ship's about to blow up, there's gonna be a draft.
欢迎来到塔迪斯
Welcome to the TARDIS.
里面比外面大多了
Much bigger on the inside.
那当然了
You'd better be.
我觉得博士想说的是
I think what the Doctor is trying to say is...
你也可以加入
You may cut in.
洛斯
Rose!
我刚想起来了
I've just remembered!
什么
What?
我会跳舞了 我会跳舞了
I can dance! I can dance!
其实 博士
Actually, Doctor,
我觉得杰克可能想跳这支舞
I thought Jack might like this dance.
我相信他会的 洛斯
I'm sure he would, Rose,
我非常确定
I'm absolutely certain
但是和谁跳呢
but who with?
下集预告
我就没一天安宁
And I was having such a nice day.
《西部邮报》
新市长 新卡迪夫
据情报
According to intelligence,
目标是斯利辛家族最后一个幸存者
the target is the last surviving member of the Slitheen family,
来自拉克西科里科弗拉帕多里斯星的犯罪家族
a criminal sect from the planet Rexicoricophalvitorius,
披着一张人皮假扮人类
masquerading as a human being zipped inside a skin-suit.
这座位于卡迪夫市中心的核电站
This nuclear power station right in the heart of Cardiff city
将会为社会各阶层带来更多工作岗位
will bring jobs for all.
然后你偏偏盖在裂缝上
And it just so happens to be right on top of the rift.
如果这个核电站熔毁
If this power station went into melt-down
整个地球都会
the entire planet would go...
走吧 你就只管走吧
Ah, Go on, then, run!
是裂缝 裂缝正在开启
It's the rift, the rift's opening.
整个城市都会消失
The whole city's gonna disappear!
时间空间都在断裂
Time and space are ripping apart.
别想卡迪夫了 它会把整个星球割裂的
Never mind Cardiff, it's gonna rip open the planet.